Good evening ladies and gentlemen. A
very warm welcome to ICICI Lombard
General Insurance Company Limited Q1 FI
2026 earnings conference call
from the senior management we have with
us today Mr. Sanjie Mantri MD and CEO of
the company Mr. Gopal Balachandran CFO
Mr. Anand Singhi chief retail and
government business Mr. Girishesh Nayak,
Chief Technology and Health Underwriting
and Claims,
Mr. Sanbep Gorada, Chief Corporate
Solutions International Bank assurance
and Mr. Gorov Aurora, Chief Reinsurance,
Underwriting and Claims for Property and
Casualty.
Please note that any statements commence
are made in today's call that may look
like forward-looking statements are
based on information presently available
to the management and do not constitute
an indication of any future performance
as future involves risks and
uncertainties which could cause results
to differ materially from the current
views being expressed.
As a reminder, all participant clients
will be in the listenonly mode and there
will be an opportunity for you to ask
questions after the presentation
concludes.
Should you need assistance during the
call, please signal an operator by
pressing star then zero on your
touchstone phone.
I now hand the conference over to Mr.
Sanjie Mantri, MD and CEO ICIC Lombard
General Insurance Limited. Thank you and
over to you sir.
>> Thank you so much sir.
Good evening to each one of you. Thank
you for joining the earnings conference
call of ICL Lombard General Insurance
Company for quarter 1 2026.
Let me give you a brief overview of the
trends we observed in the economy as
well as our industry followed by an
overview of the business. Post this our
CFO Mr. Gopal Balachend will share the
financial performance of the company for
the quarter ended June 30, 2025.
India's GDP growth for quarter four
financial year 2025 surprised positively
at 7.4%.
And the fullear growth came in at 6.5%
according to according to the data
released by Mosby.
Key macroeconomic indicators such as GST
collections and performance of
infrastructure sector indicate some
positive momentum for quarter 1
financial year 2026.
RBI's cut in the repo rate by 50 basis
point in early June 2025. income tax
incentives by government and benign
inflation is expected to augur well for
the domestic economy.
Let me now dwell on certain industry
trends which can have an impact on the
GI industry at large.
In the current quarter, the government's
continued emphasis on infrastructure
deployment by has fueled growth across
key sectors such as cement, steel,
infrastructure and capital goods. With
the banking sector remaining healthy and
capital util and capacity utilization
exceeding historical norms, any increase
in domestic demand could serve as a
catalyst for private capital
expenditure.
These factors present a positive outlook
for the commercial and of business in
coming quarters.
In quarter 1 2026, as per the data
published by CM, private car and two
wheeler segment drew by 1 and a half%
and 7.2% Y respectively.
However, in quarter 1 financial year
2026,
this is the data published by FA auto
industry has grown by 4.9%.
The private car segment grew by 2.6%
registering.97 million sales.
The two wheel segment has been seen a
modest growth of 5% contributed by
contributed by both urban and rural
consumers.
As the monsoon is forecasted to be
normal, we anticipate that it will
further fuel the rural demand.
Commercial vehicle has seen a growth of
7% which was led by strong growth in
electric free category.
As an organization, we remain optimistic
for the motor business in coming months.
The health segment remains the largest
contributor to the industry accounting
for 40.2% of the GDP mix in quarter 1
2026.
Rising hiring activity, escalating
medical cost and sustained credit growth
are the key drivers fueling continued
demand for health insurance.
However, the overall industry growth
trajectory continues to be a to be
moderated by the impact of the one by
accounting norm.
Despite this, the fundamentals of the
health insurance segment remain strong,
positioning it as a critical pillar of
long-term industry growth.
Given the favorable economic indicators
and positive regulatory environment, we
expect the general insurance industry to
continue the growth momentum in medium
to long term.
However, we remain vigilant on the
ongoing geopolitical developments which
may pose risk to both global growth and
Indian economy.
Let me now share an update on key
industry level events.
Happy to share that recently launched
campaign atakia insurance is an
commendable step by the general
insurance industry towards enhancing
awareness and consequently increasing
insurance penetration across diverse
customer segments.
This unified effort reflects the
sector's growing commitment to driving
financial protection and resilience in
India. As one of the leading players in
this industry, IPC Lombard is well
placed to contribute and benefit from
the same.
Another key event wherein the country
was deeply affected was a tragic Air
India plane crash.
We extend a sincere condolences to the
families who lost their loved ones. An
event of this magnitude can have
profound effect on all those involved.
As an industry and as an insurer, we
responded swiftly prioritizing and
supporting the affected family members
and other stakeholders during these
difficult times.
Now coming to the industry performance
for quarter 1 financial year 2026.
The GDPI grew by 8.8% 8% for quarter 1
2026.
Excluding the impact of the 1 byN
accounting norm, the GDPI grew by 12.8%
for quarter 1 2026.
Excluding crop and mass health, the GDPI
grew by 11.1% for quarter 1 2026.
Speaking on the specific segments within
the industry, the commercial segment
reported a growth of 13% for the period
ending quarter 1 financial year 2026.
The growth is majorly driven by improved
pricing in property lines of business.
The motor segment grew for the indust
growth for the industry stood at 8.7%
for the period quarter 1 2026.
The industry continues to witness
significant pricing pressure as
reflected by higher industry combined
ratio for the motor line of business.
The health segment including mass health
grew by 8.1% for the period quarter 1
2026. Within this the group health line
of business grew by 9.6% for quarter 1
whereas the retail health group stood at
9.4% 4% for quarter 1 2026 impacted by
the 1 byN accounting norm.
Speaking on the underwriting performance
of the industry overall the combined
ratio for the industry worsen to 112.6%
for financial year 2025 as against 112%
for financial year 2024.
The overall combined ratio for private
players was to 111.4 4 for financial
year 2025 from 108.7% for financial year
2024.
Industry combined working was largely
due to motor and of business. It stood
at 123.7%
for financial year 2025 resulting 118.5%
for financial year 2024.
As against this our continued focus on
driving profitable growth has helped us
to show a combined ratio of 2.8 8 for
financial year 2025 versus 103.3% for
financial year 2024.
Also, it is pertinent to note that the
company's contribution to overall
underwriting losses is at 2.7%
only with an 8.7% market share for
financial year 2025.
I will now speak about a company's
performance across key business in
quarter 1 financial year 2026.
The company's GDPR registered a growth
of 6% as against the industry growth of
8.8% for quarter 1 2026.
Exploring crop and mass health, the
company's growth was at 3.4% compared to
the industry growth of 11.1%
for quarter 1 2026.
In the commercial line segment, our
growth stood at 6.8% 8% for quarter 1
2026 as again the industry growth of 13%
for the same period. Since the industry
has seen an improvement in pricing at an
overall level however there have been
different levels of price action within
subcategories of commercial lines. We
continue to drive profitability through
food and risk selection and distribution
net growth. We have maintained a leaders
leadership position in engineering and
marine cargo line of business.
In the motor segment, our growth stood
at 3.2% for quarter 1 2026 as against
the industry growth of 8.7%.
In the backdrop of elevated competitive
intensity as stated earlier, we continue
to drive our strategy in motor insurance
based on granular portfolio segmentation
and distribution expansion.
We continue to maintain our leadership
position with a market share of 10.5%
for quarter 1, 2026. Our
portfolio mix for private car, two-heer
and commercial vehicles stood at 54.8%,
27% and 18.2% respectively in comparison
to the mix of quarter 1 2025 which stood
at 51.5%
26% and 22.5% respectively.
In health segment we grew by 1.9% for
quarter 1 2026 as against the industry
growth of 8.1%
as at quarter 1 2026 on a 1 byN basis.
Our retail health business line
continued to maintain the growth
momentum percent to which we have gained
the market share. We registered a growth
of 32.2%
as against industry growth of 9.4% as at
quarter 1 2026. The contour innovation
in retail health products and investment
in retail health distribution has helped
us to increase market share which now
stands at 3.5% for quarter 1 2026 as
against 2.9% for quarter 1 2025.
Our group health segment degree by 2.5%
for quarter 1 2026 when compared with
quarter 1 2025
resulting in a market share being at
10.1%.
This was essentially attributable
to lower growth in our group benefit
segment due to muted credit disbursement
coupled with impact of one by accounting
norms.
would now like to apprise you of other
key initiatives of our organization.
The initiatives under one team continue
to deliver measurable results
underscoring our commitment to
sustainable and profitable growth at the
organization level.
A key initiative in this journey has
been the consolidation of our customerf
facing call center into a unified one
call center aimed at standardizing
practices, enhancing operational
efficiencies and delivering a superior
customer experience through strategic
technology intervention.
The integration of process under this
initiative resulted in a 78% increase in
productivity for quarter 1 2026 along
with deduction in headcounts of the
fresh acquisition team and service team
by 22% and 10% respectively.
Our digital service engagement has gone
up to 38% in quarter 1 2026 up from 22%
in quarter 1 2025.
This was made possible through use of
artificial intelligence, voice bot,
propensity modeling and targeted
campaigns.
We further improved our efficiency in
motor claims. Our preferred partner
network serviced 74.6%
of our nonium claims in quarter 1 2026
up from 72% in quarter 1 2025.
launch launched in April of 2024. Our
issue initiative has strengthened
onground claim support for health
customers.
In quarter 1 2026, the initiative
assisted over 28,000 customers,
reflecting an increase from 8,000
customers supported in quarter 1 of
2025.
This growth highlights a continued focus
on enhancing the customer experience and
delivering timely accessible support
during the critical moments.
Our digital platform continues to aid
our growth with visitors increasing 21%
year on year and increase in fresh
business by 69% yearon year. This is
fueled by a one-stop solution I'll take
care app for all insurance and wellness
needs which surpassed 16.6 million
downloads.
Our focus on customer experience and
process efficiency has led to an NPS of
68 and 69 for health and motor claims
respectively for financial year 2025.
We have demonstrated resilience amidst
industry challenges. Maintaining a focus
on profitability
guided by our one team philosophy, we
continue to harness the power of data
technology and innovation to drive our
progress. Our robust multi-product
multi-distribution strategy allow us to
adopt swiftly and serve our customers
more effectively while delivering
profitable growth.
I will now request Gopage to take you
through the financial numbers for the
recently concluded quarter. Thanks Ajiv
uh and good evening to each one of you.
I will now give you a brief overview of
the financial performance of the
recently concluded quarter. We have
uploaded the results presentation on our
website and you can access it as we walk
you through the performance numbers.
With effect from October 1, 2024,
long-term products are accounted on a 1
byN basis as mandated by IDI. Hence, Q1
FI26 numbers are not comparable with
prior periods. Please refer to our
investor presentation for further
details. The gross direct premium income
of the company was rupees 77.35 billion
in Q1 FI26 as rupees 76.88 88 billion in
Q1 FI25 a growth of6% as against the
industry growth of 8.8%.
Excluding crop and mass sales GDP growth
of the company was 3.4% viz with the
industry growth of 11.1% in Q1 FI26 our
GDP growth during the quarter was
primarily driven by growth in the
preferred segments. So overall GDP of
our property and casualty segment grew
by 6.8% 8% to rupees 26.77 billion in Q1
FI26 as against rupees 25.08 billion in
Q1 FI25. On the retail side of the
business, the GDPI of the motor segment
was at rupees 24.44 billion in Q1 FI26
as against rupees 23.69 billion in Q1
FI25 registering a growth of 3.2%.
The advanced premium numbers for the
motor segment was at 38.07 07 billion
rupees as at June 30, 2025 as against
37.17 billion as at March 31, 2025.
GDP of the hill segment was at rupees
23.81 billion in this quarter as against
rupes 23.37 billion in Q1 last year
registering a growth of 1.9%. Our agent
which includes the point of sale
distribution count was at 1 1 lakh
43,675
as at June 30 up from 1 lakh 40,736.
This was the number as at March 31 2025.
Our combined ratio stood at 102.9%
for Q1 FI26
as against 102.3%
for Q1 FI25. Our investment asset during
the quarter rose to rups 554.53 billion
as at June 30, 2025 up from rupes 535.08
billion as at March 31, 2025. Our
investment leverage net of borrowing
remained the same at 3.74 times as at
June 30, 2025 and as at March 31 2025.
Investment income was at rupees 12.88 88
billion in Q1 FI26
as against rupees 11.28 billion in Q1
FI25.
Our capital gains net of impairment on
investment assets stood at rupees 3.8
billion in Q1 FI26 compared to rupees
2.84 billion in Q1 FI25. Our profit
before that grew by 28.4% to rupees 9.94
billion in Q1 FI26 as against rupees
7.74 billion in Q1 FI25.
Consequently, profit after tax grew by
28.7% to rupees 7.47 billion in Q1 FI26
as against rupees 5.8 billion in Q1
FI25. Return on average equity was at
20.5% in Q1 FI26 as against 19.1% in Q1
FI25. Soy ratio was at 2.7 times as at
June 30, 2025 as against 2.69 times as
at March 31, 2025. This continues to be
higher than the minimum regulatory
requirement of 1.5 times.
As I conclude, I would like to reassure
that we remain committed and focused on
our strategy of innovation and driving
profitable growth, consistent and
sustainable value creation for all our
stakeholders while continually ensuring
that the interest of the industry and
our policy holders is in the forefront
at all times. Thank you and we'll be
open to take questions.
>> Thank you very much. We will now begin
the question and answer session. Anyone
who wishes to ask questions may press
star and one on the touchstone
telephone. If you wish to remove
yourself from the question queue, you
may press star and participants are
requested to use handsets while asking
questions. Ladies and gentlemen, we will
wait for a moment while the question
queue assembles.
To ask questions, please press star and
one.
First question is from Nishin Chawat
from Kota. Please go ahead.
>> Uh yeah hi uh thanks for uh taking my
question. Uh my my question is actually
on the commercial lines of uh you know
businesses uh you know somewhere at the
beginning you mentioned that uh pricing
has improved uh in this segment but uh I
think at the same time you also said
that you know there are different levels
of pricing and as I see you've kind of
you know shrunk the market share a
little bit in this segment. uh so just
curious what is your view on this
segment and uh do you expect this to be
uh you know a profitability accretive uh
in this financial year.
>> Sure I think thank thanks Dish for your
question. Uh the simple answer is I mean
uh overall yes with the overall
sentiment and traging getting better we
do expect it to be more profitable. If
you remember uh last year when we were
you know reaching out in every possible
quarter we had spoken about the
excessive uh uh intensity and aggression
on the pricing front. Uh certainly
there's a bit of a semblance overall. Uh
but uh we also said along with the
multiple sections and competitive
intensity that we have seen what we have
done is distributionled growth primarily
because on the larger corporate side of
the larger risk still there has been
some bit of a excessive pricing which
has come in. We've done what is required
uh to drive profitable growth for us. uh
your your seek on do you expect it to
continue? Uh our firm belief is yes uh
and what market is doing at this point
is pricing this appropriately
uh which was not happening otherwise in
the previous year.
>> So this should actually be a kind of you
know a profitability accretive this year
is what we are trying to say.
>> I mean it's very difficult to forecast
the simple answer is pricing improved it
should be better than what it is. Uh but
you know fire as a business plan has to
play out over quarters because it's
driven by very low frequency and very
high severity. Uh but it should be
profitive. It should be profitable
overall. My answer is yes. Uh but it
will have to play out because it's
driven by extreme losses as and when it
happens if it happens.
>> Uh yes of course. Uh the other question
is uh you know on the loss ratio in the
health business uh if you could uh help
help us uh you know split it between the
uh you know retail and the uh group
business.
So listen uh uh I'm giving the group
numbers first which is corporate health
Q1 last year was 97.9 this is the last
year Q1
>> 97.9 that number for Q1 this year is at
95.7
uh on the retail intermittity again
similar periods Q1 last year was 72.5
Q1 this year is 74.3
>> uh got it thank you very much and all
the best
>> thanks thank Thank you.
>> Thank you. The next question is from
Madukar Lada from Nwama Wealth
Management. Please go ahead
seem to have lost the line from Madukar.
We'll move to the next question. The
next question is from Pra Jane from
Motila Roswal. Please go ahead.
>> Yeah, just uh just a follow up on the
loss ratio of the retail health. uh you
you mentioned it's gone up from 72.5
to 74.3
given that we would have had a very
strong growth on the fresh premium uh
would you say that the severity and the
frequency of uh retail indemnity has
gone up substantially.
So Kesh I think u if you remember even
last year first quarter we did kind of
talk about a slight increase in
incidences uh so we do see that playing
out even for quarter one of this year so
there has been definitely an increase in
uh incidents but uh as you would have
seen when we even when we started the
last year quarter one number was 72.5
but by the time we ended if you would
have seen the number on a full year
basis our retailers block ratio ended
about 67.9
>> uh so and exactly to your point I I
think uh what's helping us is uh the
growth that we are seeing uh largely
kind of aided by the ele elevate product
offering that we have been talking
about. I think that continues to kind of
do well and therefore this is just
quarter one and our expectation is
pretty much in line with the range of
loss ratios that we have chosen. I think
in all fairness the expectation is that
we should kind of uh end the end the
year in that same loss ratio range of 65
to 70%. that the range that's the range
at which we are comfortable with and as
of now I think things seems to be pretty
much looking around uh within that range
uh this is just a quarter one uh
phenomena
>> just uh and again the 32% growth that
you have seen on the retail retail
health uh how much would you how much of
that would be say portability and how
much would it be from uh say you know
first time customers to the industry can
you give some qualitative comments is
there because that will help us
understand the quality of business.
>> So pre in general I think if you look at
it I think our market share has been
very low right so I think uh as a
company we have had an aggregate market
share of 2.9 I think we have moved the
needle which is what we talked about to
move at about 3.5%. And the endeavor for
us is to obviously kind of make sure
that again if you remember last quarter
four we did speak about the initiatives
that we're trying to do on retaining our
own customers. So therefore in that
sense obviously that's a that's an area
where we are actively focusing on so
that we are able to kind of improve our
own retention and two again the
objective will be to try and see if we
can get more customers particularly
which are new to insurance. uh to your
point on what could be the extent of
portability we don't separately call out
that number but I think clearly from our
standpoint I think what we can talk
about is on a relative basis I think the
proportion of what we would have seen as
a rollover whether it is quarter 1 or
quarter four of last year visually what
we have seen in quarter 1 I think
definitely that mix is lower
>> okay and uh just coming back to the uh
the motor segment uh what is your
thoughts on motor DP price side do you
think that can come through. So hi P
Sanj there we are also as much aware as
you are there is enough and more news
that we can uh we are you know ourselves
seeing that something is expected has
the industry made the representation
answer is yes uh uh but we would not
have any update beyond that uh but it's
it's it's kind of expected uh but in our
working and in our thought process and
in our sourcing the way we operate we
take things as they exist at this point
of time where there is no TP hike uh but
we we must share the optimism which is
there overall that since for last four
years almost there's been very little
that has happened on the TP side uh some
uh increase uh would be a relief for the
industry overall
>> and just follow up on that can it happen
without a care person and the regulators
So uh the manner in which it gets
announced is more in consultation with
IIDA. So uh it can happen technically
but again this is something which is
beyond our embit and we don't want to
you know further uh devel uh
structurally from whatever it's uh known
to us it's possible. I mean go for any
of this.
>> So I think only other thing that I would
add price is I think uh definitely what
warrants a price increase. I think this
is what I think the industry has been
largely looking at as in for example
again similar to what we have been
speaking which is when we see court
compensation or court award getting
exhibited and the element of uh uh claim
inflation that you're required to build
as a part of the loss cost. Definitely
there is every reason for us to believe
that uh one should definitely seek a
price change. Exactly when will it
happen? How how it would get notified? I
think honestly we'll have to wait for
it. But there is definitely a case for
the industry to seek a price increase
given the fact that for the last few
years uh we have not necessarily seen in
that sense a meaningful price increase
on third party.
>> Thank you. The next question is from Sri
Ga from a Wendis Park. Please go ahead.
>> Yeah. And thank you for the opportunity.
I see the fire growth for for us has
been lower compared to industry and and
we invariably are the market leaders
after probably new in that business. So,
so they just wanted to understand that
given given the bulk of the business
happens in first quarter in in
commercial lines is it fair to say that
um maybe because of the pricing
environment um our expected growth which
was maybe meaningfully very higher will
remain at the current levels for the
full year.
>> Fair question. uh I if it is uh
something which you have to think in as
a friend I believe our growth can also
increase uh overall in coming quarters
but the bulk of the booking booking does
happen in first quarter to that extent
mathematically speaking uh you are right
uh however progressively last year the
discounting kept increasing as quarters
kept happening right so the market kept
hitting new levels of discount so to
that extent if there is some assemblage
that is coming in the industry should
show further positive trend as far as Yi
growth is concerned and in line with
that we would also like to believe in
that ourselves to say that we will also
see that positive trend continuing
however whether we will be able to
bridge the delta that is existing in
quarter one uh that our endeavor
obviously is uh to get that managed over
quarter and see that we stay where we
want to uh
it will be purely a function of uh how
the pricing elements are working out in
different sections and we will take a
call accordingly.
Got it. Got it. And and the second thing
which I wanted to understand is that if
I look at the motor growth based on the
mix what you disclosed in the PPT it
seems that you you grew largely in the
commercial vehicles while while your
growth in two wheelers and cars looks
okay compared to overall growth. So, so
is it largely because of the um
intensive competitive environment or or
or or we reccalibrating compared to what
we did last year um in that line of
business.
>> Uh no no I think you're again spot on.
Uh see beginning of the year again the
normal inflation and all of that comes
through our respective loss ratio that
is expected to happen. uh and if there's
no TP hike it does make uh the overall
map adverse and and logically speaking
the cost of acquisition to that extent
should get adjusted so that uh the TPI
if it's not there still the overall map
falls in place uh we did realize that
the market overall did not change the
trajectory and we felt to be a bit more
prudent uh at this point of time you
you're spot on yes that's what is
reflective of uh it is not that uh we
don't want to uh do the right thing and
see TV CV also showing positivity but uh
it's purely a function of selection
which has made us uh come out the way we
have come out in terms of outcome but we
don't want to do it and you know that
the cost of profitability
yes so basically in simple words if if
there's a price like say in couple of
months um then easy trade to say that
you you might see a pullback or or a
better growth in in CV segment. So the
again the function is uh uh it's it's a
function of how the market reacts
further suppose I'm just giving a
scenario the simple answer to what you
said is logically yes
it should work out what you're saying
but supposedly the market reacts again
much more sharply and ends up throwing a
lot more money
>> in terms of costition we will again end
up calibrating so
logically what you're saying should
happen but we'll have to wait till it
plays out.
>> Got it. Got it. Perfect. And and last
one crop insurance 1425 crores what we
did last year. Um uh today today we are
doing just 18 crores in the current
quarter. Maybe timing difference. So
given given you mentioned in the PP that
you won few clusters. So so is it fair
to say that there will be year-on-year
growth in the crop business in the
current year?
>> Uh year oneon-year growth difficult to
admit. See for crop most of the things
will come up for bidding next financial
year. Uh this year there are very few
actions. So uh as l could have it the
mahastra where we were already there at
this year should have lasted has gone
for retendering consequent to which we
had to rebid. uh whether we will to
match it or grow only time will tell but
not too many opportunities at this point
of time uh to see that we can exceed
that number at least at this juncture.
>> Yeah,
>> thank you.
>> All right,
>> the next question is from Nidesh Jane
from Invest. Please go ahead.
>> Uh hi sir. Uh thanks for the
opportunity. So my question is on
competitive intensity. So which are
these players who are uh who are
engaging in intense compet competition
in at this point in time uh because uh
last time these were mostly private
sector players but this time if you look
at the data industry data the market
share gain is happening from PSU
players.
>> So what is driving that and how do you
see that ending up? Uh last time a
couple of players have so shown very
high losses and then competent intensity
reduces for one year but again we are
again seeing that competent intensity is
increasing. So how do you see this plays
plays out and what are the timelines
let's say when when this will taper off.
>> So I think the way I think we would
respond is u I think all of this
thankfully is public information.
Therefore I think the market clearly
knows which companies are aggressive
which companies are kind of gaining
market share. So uh without specifically
kind of getting into names um I think
this is all there in the public domain.
I think all that I which is what we kind
of put out as a part of the uh opening
transcript as in to say that and which
is which is what we called out even last
year. I think on motor specifically if
you would have seen honestly there was
an expectation last year for the
industry to actually see an improvement
in combines uh which if you remember
kind of kind of finally ended the year
with a combined ratio of almost 124% for
the industry as a whole compared to
roughly about 118% that we had seen uh
one year back. uh so so that's that's
how we have kind of headed into the
current year and that's also the reason
why if you would have seen for us I
think relative to the industry growth in
motor which has been a single-digit
number of roughly about 8% plus uh our
growth in motor has been 3.2%. Uh so
that's again a conscious call. Now how
long can some of these players subsist
uh elevated competitive intensity? The
good news is again each for each of the
companies there is public disclosures on
their outcomes in terms of combined
ratios. Uh some of the companies have uh
while majority of the companies we have
the full year numbers some companies
possibly could have announced numbers
even for quarter 1 as we speak. Uh so
clearly it seems to suggest that the
market continues to stay uh competitive
at 124% plus honestly we don't
necessarily kind of see uh at an
aggregate level to be very uh in that
sense gaining market share but within
the segments obviously we will kind of
grow where we think it is appropriate
and you know just to add to it uh as an
entity we had to show tremendous uh
patience uh uh if you you know go back
into history. Last year in H1 we had
gained then we kind of moderated and
that kind of moderation continued but we
know that uh if there is uh this kind of
intensity which is at a very different
level at this point of time we are
willing to uh uh wait it out uh and we
know those cycles will come and we'll
have our opportunity.
>> Yeah the the only thing is that the time
difference between cycle is quite short.
We are just getting one year of uh time
period where the competitive intensity
is okay but again then some new set of
players keep coming in and competitive
intensity increases then so it's not
that the two three year period there is
an upcycle in terms of uh reasonable
competitive intensity in the sector.
>> Okay fair point but the fact of the
matter is if new players are coming they
also over long term are expecting value
to be created and that's why we
attracting new players. Suppose there
are no new players coming also also
speaks out the fact that it's not doing
enough to attract capitals. Uh frankly
speaking my view to that decision is the
other way around and while that we would
love to have periods of you know uh 3
years two years as you mentioned uh but
we are very well equipped as a multi-led
multi- product multi- channelannel uh
entity to manage these kinds of
variability. It's part of our day-to-day
existence. So at times from a investor
standpoint when you look at it you
wonder what's happening uh but as a
company you know and you see the numbers
from you know almost 2008 since the
retire thing happened the industry grew
at 15% and there about around that
region but we have probably grown at 13
and a half almost a percentage and a
half lower over 2008 to 2025
uh but the fiery profit growth of the
industry is 10 and probably 8 to 10% and
ours is almost 20%. So uh we we back
ourselves in these times also. We would
love to have it the way you are saying
uh and this keeps us agile also. So it
really doesn't worry us but from your
standpoint maybe you've got a point.
>> Sure. Thank you. So that's it.
>> Thanks. Thanks.
>> Thank you.
Before we take the next question, a
reminder to participants that you may
press star and one to join the question
queue.
The next question is from Shri Shivani
from CLSA. Please go ahead.
>> Yeah, thank you for the opportunity. I
have two questions. First is on the uh
on the tragedy that you mentioned about.
I just wanted to understand has uh how
much of the claims have been uh uh
included in our uh performance this
quarter u the hull losses have they come
in in this quarter or whether they're
going to come in the next quarter and
and I'm assuming there will also be the
personal accident bit uh so that can be
spread over some time I understand but
uh what has happened with the aviation
claim that I wanted to understand uh
second is on the long-term policies. So,
um I remember when this was launched,
there was a bit of confusion or not
confusion, the entire way in which you
are paying out commissions to your
distributor on the long-term policy has
also changed, right? It'll be in that
1/3 format or whatever whatever one by
end format. Uh so, has the behavior of
the distributor changed uh now that
you're 69 months into it? Uh in which
product segments has it changed? Are
some product segments going to become
one-year product only instead of being
long-term because of this policy change?
Some commentary around that. Those are
my two questions. Thank you.
>> Sure. So uh so share on the first one I
think again as as we have always said I
think it's very difficult to kind of
comment on uh individual claims. I think
what we can say for sure is uh uh what
we have which is what we have been kind
of telling even earlier at the time when
the incident had happened. uh given the
exposure that we have on the risk the
impact that we on that we have on the
net they have been completely kind of
provided for. So whatever results that
you see uh for quarter one factors in
for the likely uh impact of claims
because honestly we will not know when
the estimate will eventually play out
and but I think it is well within our
ability to kind of observe such losses
that's primarily the business that we
are in and therefore to that extent I
think we have been able to kind of
provide for uh estimate this is uh what
we have as of 30th of June. uh to your
second point on uh long-term policies. I
think that's a flexibility which I think
clearly the market has uh got. I think
they have to decide in terms of how do
they want to incentivize sourcing of
policies. Uh as we speak, you're right,
we are into the third quarter of the
change. Uh market still continues to
exhibit differentiated behavior in terms
of some of them exhibiting uh some of
them kind of seeking a friend, some of
them obviously willing to kind of take
over a period of time. But if you ask us
has there been any major shift in the
behavior relative to what we had seen in
Q3 and Q4 the short answer is no. We
have not necessarily seen any major.
>> No. So so there you know I I totally
agree you that uh as Gopal said that in
certain concepts of long-term uh there
can be differential practice but more so
on the health side the industry has been
very unified in terms of procuring
long-term products. uh initially in
initial quarters we did see the
long-term sourcing getting impacted for
us because we had moved in line with the
regulation and others had not moved. Uh
but uh uh thank god in that sense that
now the practice has been uniformly
addressed by each one of them and from
there on we all see uh those numbering
back. So to that extent here it is uh a
positive sign and uh the partners are
also finding an obvious benefit of doing
long-term fin policies for the
customers. Yes. So there is uh normaly
as far as health part of the business is
concerned on the retail side.
>> Got it. Got it. And just on the first
question just a followup sorry uh how
much can we say is the uh is the total
combined ratio impact of that event if
there's a number
>> it's been and the fact that we are not
calling out otherwise we would have
called out that is
>> the usual share
>> okay
>> and these are all estimates it is 55 but
it's uh addressed at this juncture and
we don't think it's appropriate to call
out that Sure.
Sure. It's okay. Um, thank you so much.
This was very useful. Thank you.
>> Thanks.
>> Thank you.
Next question is from Madukar Lada from
Noama Wealth Management. Please go
ahead.
>> Hi. Uh, thank you for taking my
question. Uh, I I got bit connection in
between. So maybe you know this feeling
if I repeat uh so when you point out
comparative intensity
uh are we seeing some letdown in
comparative intensity due to
uh increased uh due to probably slightly
lower commission payouts and and because
uh ratios remain high for a lot of
private uh guys. Uh and is it is it uh
is it is it because of that that the PSU
uh guys are increasing their share or is
it that the PSU PS PSU players pricing
itself is uh lower. Uh so so so that was
uh one question I mean you know why uh
and what is your expectation given that
you know now uh considerable amount of
time has passed and low uh levels still
remain very high for uh a lot of the
guys. So um so what is your expectation
uh on on what can happen over there?
Thanks.
>> Yeah. So Madukar I think uh you are
absolutely right. I think what will be a
key key watch will be because this will
be the third year of the glide path that
the regulator had uh uh announced in
2024. Um even if you look at public
disclosure of all the companies which is
now out for FI25 as we speak uh it's
been about 50% of those companies are
still yet to tow the line uh within the
limit of 30 or 35% that the regulator
has stipulated. So hence that will be
something that's that will be closely
watched for. Uh clearly if you recolct
even last year when the regulator had
kind of looked at these companies they
have been asked to kind of give a clear
road map every quarter uh in terms of
what is their plan to achieve the
numbers uh within that limit of 30 or
35. So hence that will be clearly a key
determinant for most of the players who
have not necessarily yet met the limits.
uh what could happen in terms of the
competitive intensities again which is
what we responded in response to one of
the earlier calls which is to say that I
think players who have chosen to be very
aggressive in the last 2 three years I
think you can clearly see basis their
public disclosures their combined ratios
have got significantly impacted and they
are kind of clearly calibrating growth
numbers uh and hence of course this is
market so obviously there are other set
of players who choose to then get a
aggressive in entirety when you put all
of this together which is why we called
out industry combined ratio still
continues to remain elevated at 113 and
within that motor continues to stay
elevated at 124. Okay. How long can this
subsist? Honestly,
honestly we believe that you cannot
continue to lose 25 cents to a dollar uh
for a very long period of time.
And also madukar we also believe that
sometimes the solution you're seeking on
the e can be worse than the problem and
that's what gopal is talking about you
may want to chase uh business which
comes on a lower cost of acquisition at
a pricing which is very aggressive now
uh clearly if that's the solution
industry seeks uh to manage the glide
path uh we will uh uh let them take that
call uh and to be fair it's each one to
his own self on that uh but we'll have
to see how it plays out
>> right also uh a followup uh see even on
health because of the long-term policies
um
how has industry sort of reacted in
terms of you know payment of uh
commission over there on the long-term
policies that's uh one part of the
question are most people uh you know uh
to that is it's all done by hand. We pay
it on a yearly basis for long-term
health policy. Yeah.
>> Okay. And on on renewal uh uh premiums
uh are we are we seeing some sort of
reduction in commission in in uh in the
mill u because that was one of the
expectations also given.
>> Yes, it is and you are spot on.
uh definitely there's a delta which
exists between the fresh sourcing of
health and the renewal and to be fair
it's at the industry level it's not only
for ICO
>> right I um got it got it thank you
thanks
>> thank you thank you
>> thank you before we take the next
question a reminder to participants that
you may press star and one to ask
questions
the next question is from the gosh from
Please go ahead.
>> Hi sir. Uh just two questions. One on
the group health part. Obviously u you
had kind of moderated your growth u
trajectory somewhere towards the second
of last year given the competitive
pressure. So I just want to get some
sense you know with your base kind of
normalizing from let's say the second
half of this year. I mean how do you see
the growth in that part of the segment
and the competitive intensity your loss
ratios are also kind of improved a
little bit on a y basis. So how do you
see that segment behaving on the
corporate employer employee side and
second on the retail health portion of
the business? I mean um you know I think
this question was asked previously also
but you know from that calculation it
suggests that loss ratios on the back
are probably kind of operating at levels
which is uh which may be a little bit
higher than what the industry averages
are or maybe your stated averages of
around 65 to 70% steady state run rate
on the backbook I'm just talking about.
So uh first of all is the assumption
correct and secondly I mean if yes and
how do you kind of uh aim to recalibrate
it?
>> So group health dependent I think uh I
think the call is pretty much similar to
what we spoke about on the rest of the
lines as well. Now this is a segment
where even Sanji had spoken about let's
say typically you get get to exhibit
maybe slightly chunky premium but maybe
comes at a very relatively lower cost of
acquisition. So hence uh competitive
intensity continues to be higher on that
particular segment given the fact what I
spoke about on possibly some companies
wanting to ride this segment of business
to meet their uh expensive management
obligations within that is how we have
played out our growth. So we will watch
for the development in case uh I think
if you see signs of easing for let's say
for companies who have to meet their um
then obviously I think we are well
placed uh to write the risk back the
good news as we keep saying in our in
our businesses majority of our risks are
one-year risks and therefore to that
extent our ability to possibly get it
back uh is always there with us and on
the second one I think
>> on on the second one on the retail
help uh it was more with respect to
sorry loss issue the the loss rats which
you're talking I think Gopalar has
already spoken about it uh we do believe
that coming quarters so this is uh you
know the mix the way it comes out and
the lot of NP that comes in and we have
seen a bit of a frequency spike here and
there uh but your backend calculation
spot on and we do believe that uh as a
company we would fare a lot better in
coming quarters as the growth of new
would start uh you know uh overall
impacting our loss ratios positively. So
your calculation is right and we are
also expecting a similar trend.
>> Uh got it. Uh thank you sir and all the
best.
>> Thank you. Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> The next question is from Mirage who's
an individual investor for
>> call on hold. Please stay on
Mirage's line seem to be on hold.
Uh that was the last question in queue.
I would now like to hand the conference
over to Mr. Sanjiv Makri for any closing
comments.
>> Yeah. No. Uh thank you so much for
joining. I think you all had a long day
back toback calls. There were uh live
potential now Lombard. So enough and
more calls. uh
look I mean we've spoken overly what we
want to focus on and uh we look forward
to interacting with each one of you in
the course of the quarter. All the best
and take care of yourself. Thank you so
much.
>> Thank you very much
on behalf of ICI Lumbar General
Insurance Company Limited. That
concludes the conference. Thank you for
joining us ladies and gentlemen. You may
now disconnect your lines.